Chelsea Town

www.chelseatown.com

c: 541-350-5121 e: me@chelseatown.com a: Bend, OR

Summary

Chelsea Town

Frontend Engineer

Experienced Frontend Engineer specializing in HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, UI/UX, QC and design. Accumulated experience of 20 years of code development. Detailed experience includes HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, APIs, jQuery, jQuery mobile, Bootstrap, Sass, Responsive Web Design, Angularjs, load times, GitHub, browser developer tools, intensive quality control experience and debugging, Sublime Text, Notepad++, cross-browser dev, Desk.com, WordPress, design creation and implementation, SEO, Windows, Mac, and mobile environments. Comfortable in a fast-paced, evolving tech environment. Naturally organized and excel at customer communication. Always striving to learn and maintain modern tech knowledge.

Work History

Sept 2010 -Aug 2015

Frontend Engineer

Smartwaiver | Bend, OR

- Developing and maintaining front-end HTML, CSS, JavaScript for company website with occasional back-end modifications. Work directly with backend developer to finalize and launch websites and apps. Use and Implement team tools, command prompt GitHub, Asana, Desk.com.
- Product, software and application testing cross platform and cross browser via tangible device and *Cross Browser Testing*. Extensive compatibility testing, pinpointing bug/error location, revised testing until completion. No major bugs ever released.
- Creating website layout, produce original designs, icons and visual graphics, landing pages, print media, swag and signs. Expert in Adobe Suite.
- API testing, implementation and troubleshooting for in-house API and Google API, as well as any Webhook issues.
- Responsible for FareHarbor partnership with Smartwaiver.
- Reaching out to clients, developing relationships and follow through till completed.
- Customer support, modifying and creating new accounts, troubleshooting and interaction with possible conversions. Contact through live chat, CRM, Skype.
- · Video creation & completion, copy, editing, and voiceover using Camtasia.
- Total maintenance, bug decoding and problem solving for forward progression and profitability of *Spadout.com*.
- Work as a team member from pre-opening day through post-profitable, with constant adaptations as the company grew.
- · Participation in interviews and decision making on company employee hiring.

July 2005 -Sept 2010

Web Developer & Graphic Designer

The Nugget | Sisters, OR

- Create and modify graphic media for a wide variety of clients.
- Develop magazine and web media. Adjust for variances of different types of print mediums and visuals.
- Maintain company's social media sites with creative, new avenues.
- · Proofreading and editing copy.
- Maintain client accounts on a weekly basis, check-in, revise and compile advertising marketing direction.
- Leadership and management of large accounts with a one on one relationship. Problem solving for clients and developing marketing platform.

Oct 2000 -2012

Freelance Web Developer

Chelsea Town | Bend, OR

- Develop client websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, furnish design comps, multiple revision development plans, onsite shopping, PayPal, Login, CRM and Database management, product galleries and forms.
- · Provide revisions and updates.
- Maintain client's social media presence in various applications, mailing lists.
- · Creative, copy, icons, logos, and designs.

Skills

Primary Skills

- HTML CSS JavaScript jQuery GitHub APIs UI/UX jQuery Mobile
- · Software and Product Testing · Responsive Web Design · Speed and load times
- · Angularis · WordPress · Bootstrap · PHP · MySQL · Cross-platform device / OS
- $\cdot \, \mathsf{Troubleshooting} \cdot \mathsf{Adobe} \, \mathsf{Photoshop} \cdot \, \mathsf{Adobe} \, \mathsf{Illustrator} \cdot \, \mathsf{Adobe} \, \mathsf{InDesign} \cdot \mathsf{SEO}$
- DreamWeaver Clean, Documented Code Copywriting & Editing Client Portfolio Management Team Project Collaboration

. .

Other Skills

· Video Creation & Editing · Voice Over · Customer Technical Support · Client Relationships · German · Running · CrossFit · Foosball · Nutrition

Education

June 2002

Computer Graphics, BA

University of California, Santa Barbara

Study of computer design with an emphasis on software programs, layout, design fundamentals, overall comprehension of design and viewer/user. Individual project presentation, design progression.

PHP & MySQL, Adult Education June 2012-2014

Central Oregon Community College

Further education with adult online courses to define backend developer knowledge, development in personal and business website creation.

German Language

Goethe-Institut, Prien Am Chiemsee, Germany June-Sept

Intensive, no-English, immersive study of the German Language in the South of Germany. On-campus living with reports and presentations in German. 1998